太空堡垒卡拉狄加 【前情提要】
BALTAR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
不  对不起 我不能再这样了
Oh, no, I'm sorry. I can't live like this.
我不会离婚 你也不会对你妻子不忠
So, I won't divorce and you won't cheat.
这让我们处于何种境地?
So, where does that leave us?
进退两难
Trapped.
这是什么?
What's this?
这是一份对所有犯人的草率处决书
D'ANNA: This orders the summary executions
他们的名字都在下一页
of all the detainees listed on the next page.
需要你的签名
It requires your signature.
这是死刑执行书 你看过这份名单上的名字吗?
GAETA: This is a death warrant! Have you seen the names on this list?
你知道他们会怎么做吗?
Do you have any idea what they're about to do out there?
如果你确实是赛昂人 "终极五人"之一的话
NO. 6: If you really are a Cylon, a member of the Final Five,
这些感情也只是你的一段程序
these feelings are just part of your programming.
只有进入神庙的人  才能看到"终极五人"
The Final Five, revealed only to those who enter the Temple.
只有被神选中的人才能看到  被神选中的人才能看到
Only to the Chosen One... The Chosen One...
你们两人的宿命将分道扬镳 盖尤斯
NO. 6: Her destiny will part company from yours, Gaius.
她不是被神所选中的  而你是
She's not the Chosen One, you are.
神啊  在我死前告诉我真相
Dear God, tell me the truth before I die.
我是赛昂人吗?
Am I a Cylon?
欢迎回家  总统阁下
Welcome home, Mr. President.
闭上眼 安睡吧
BALTAR:Close your eyes, go to sleep
小宝贝在摇篮中数绵羊
Baby's in the cradle counting sheep
爬上你那座梦之屋
Climb up to your house of dreams
小宝贝在摇篮中快快睡
Baby's in the cradle fast asleep
我要在睡醒前死掉吗
Should I die before I wake...
不好意思 现编的
Sorry. Improvising.
你这么做是对的  盖尤斯
You're doing the right thing, Gaius.
盖尤斯?      什么?
Gaius? What?
对 对
Yes. Yes.
醒醒!
Wake up!
闭上眼 安睡吧
NO. 6 AND BALTAR:Close your eyes, go to sleep
小宝贝在摇篮中数绵羊
Baby's in the cradle counting sheep
爬上你那座梦之屋
Climb up to your house of dreams...
等等
Wait.
等一下
Wait a moment.
我需要些时间整理一下思绪
I need some time to think this through.
太迟了
Too late, Gaius.
是揭开谜底的时候了
It's time to learn the truth.
中士    抱歉  长官
Sergeant. Sorry, sir.
没有总统的直接授权
No one's allowed to speak to the prisoner
任何人不准与犯人交谈
without direct Presidential authorization.
我已经得到了批准 需要立即去犯人谈话
I already have authorization. I need to speak to the prisoner, now.
退后  长官
Step back, sir.
就这样  盖尤斯
That's it, Gaius.
深呼吸
Deep breaths.
就这样  盖尤斯  深呼吸  深呼吸
That's it, Gaius. Deep breaths. Deep breaths.
第一次是最难受的 你表现得很不错
First time's the hardest. You're doing wonderfully.
我还活着?
I'm alive?
我还活着
I'm alive.
谢天谢地  我还活着
Thank God, I'm alive!
我不是总说要有信心么
I always told you to have faith.
就是说我没有背叛任何人
Then no one was betrayed.
我本就不是他们中的一员
I was never one of them.
我是你们的人
I am one of you.
你是这样认为的吗  盖尤斯?
Is that what you think, Gaius?
我就知道 我就知道
I knew it. I knew it.
我早就知道自己与众不同
I always knew I was different.
异于常人
Special.
也许还有少许天分
Maybe a little gifted. I was...
呃
Uh... Uh...
这可有点狠呐 挺疼的
That's a bit rough, actually.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
你错了  盖尤斯
You're wrong, Gaius.
你不是赛昂人 你是人类  你死定了
You're not Cylon. You're human. And you're dead!
他活过来了
He's alive.
我去叫科特尔
I'll get Cottle.
反正肯定会让你大吃一惊的
I'm just saying. You're gonna be surprised.
恩  少校     这边
Yeah, well, Major... Right this way.
老乔之家 我都没去过酒吧
Joe's? Well, I think I've seen a bar before.
真的假的啊?  来吧
You got to be frakking kidding me. Come on.
这边  老乔    蒂罗尔轮机长 欢迎你
Hey, this way. Hey, Joe. Chief Tyrol, welcome.
少校的朋友就是我的朋友
Any friend of the Major's is a friend of mine,
也就是说 给你的全是好货
which means you get the good stuff.
多谢您  那我就不客气了 反正今晚我也不回家了
Thank you very much. Don't mind if I do. I'm not going home tonight, so...
怎么  你和凯莉闹矛盾了?
Why? You and Cally have a fight?
你没听到我们吵架?  我们以为都可以卖票参观了
You didn't hear us? I figured we could have sold tickets.
啊…
Ah...
敬婚姻 这也是我们开酒吧的原因
To marriage, why we build bars.
对  老乔
Yeah. Joe!
我已经警告过你们 "睡眠剥夺"的危险性
COTTLE: I warned about the dangers of sleep deprivation.
精神病可以促使一个人做出怪异的举动
Psychosis can make a man do strange things.
波塔尔的绝食抗议对他也没好处
And Baltar's little hunger strike is not helping, either.
这混蛋求死心切  我看咱们就成全他
Bastard wants to die that bad, I say let him.
我们至少要让波塔尔开口说话
Bottom line, we need Baltar to talk.
如果赛昂人也看到了那个标记
If the other Cylons saw the same symbols that we saw,
他们可能 已经踏上去地球的路了
they could be on their way to Earth.
可能已经在途中设好了埋伏
They could be setting up an ambush by now.
我看今晚过后  他求死的决心会更大
I'm betting that after tonight, he'll be more willing.
医生  再等一到两个小时  我要让他有根有据
Doc, wait an hour or two. I want him cogent.
也别让他挨饿
I also don't want him to starve.
你说我能怎么办?
What do you expect me to do about it?
确保让他开口吃东西
I expect you to make sure he eats.
我会在牢房里安装监视器
I'll see about putting security cameras in that cell.
盖塔先生
Mr. Gaeta?
为什么你要在半夜去见波塔尔博士?
What exactly were you doing going to see Dr. Baltar in the middle of the night?
呃…
Um...
我睡不着
I couldn't sleep,
还有我觉得他可能愿意和我说话
and I guess I thought he might be willing to talk to me.
我们理解 就把审讯的事宜交给我们吧
We understand. Just leave his interrogation to us.
这是当然
Of course.
你熬夜了
You're up late.
轮机长代我向你问好
You know, the Chief says hi.
他也是你的酒友?
He one of your new drinking buddies?
我本打算请你去  可你有言在先不喜欢喝酒
You know, I would invite you, but you made it very clear it's not your thing.
对  可你喜欢  我又没问你这件事
No, it's your thing, and that's not what I was asking.
我五点起来还要去汇报
I got a briefing at 0500.
我们明天还一起吃晚饭吗?
Are we still on for dinner tomorrow?
吃啊
Yeah.
因为我已经和别人换班了    好
Because I already switched watches. Sure.
夫妻俩偶尔共进晚餐…
Just be nice for a husband and wife to occasionally...
当我没说
Forget it.
谢谢 不用关门了
Thank you. You can leave the door open.
是  女士
Yes, Madam.
你好呀
Hi.
这步棋走得漂亮  总统女士
Touch茅, Madam President.
我不想看你受罪
I have no wish to see you suffer.
是吗?
Really?
我刚享受完被人用一条管子从鼻子强行插进去 直达咽喉的过程
I've just had the pleasure of having a tube forced up my nose and down my throat.
人总要吃饭的
Everybody's got to eat.
这是为了你好
It's for your own good.
在新卡布里卡我们的人在你的牢房里所受的苦
And it's nothing compared to what many of our people were subjected to
要比这有过之而无不及
in your jail cells on New Caprica.
不是我的牢房 是赛昂人的
Not my jails. The Cylons'.
现在看来 这不过是学术讨论了  博士
An academic distinction at this point, Doctor.
谁都不愿意这么做
You know, none of us are enjoying this.
你还是老实交代吧
So why don't you just tell me what I need to know,
那样也就不会受这个罪了 这我可以保证
and your suffering will come to an end. And I promise you this.
对于赛昂人的计划或去向  我一无所知
I know nothing about the Cylons' plans or their whereabouts.
在那间神庙里  我什么也没看见
I witnessed nothing in that Temple.
毫不夸张地说 有关赛昂人的情况
My information on Cylon intelligence
我所知有限
is limited, to say the least.
在殖民地遭到袭击之前  你可曾有高级安全通行证?
Prior to the attack on the Colonies, did you have high-level security clearance?
有  那又怎样?  你告诉过其他人吗?
Yeah. So, what? Did you tell anybody about it?
你让别人登陆过国防主机吗?
Did you let someone into the defense mainframe?
小心了  盖尤斯
Careful, Gaius.
在袭击之前 我看到你和一名金发女郎在一起
The blonde woman that I saw you with on Caprica just prior to the attack?
她会毫不犹豫地把你扔出过渡舱
She'll flush you out of an airlock without a moment's hesitation.
当然  除非…  你已经不怕这些了
Unless, of course, that prospect no longer frightens you.
谎言
Lies.
还是谎言
All lies.
依旧在重复从前那些谎话
A rehash of all the other old lies.
我没有协力参与对我们同类的种族灭绝
I did not collude in the genocide of my own people.
嗯
Mmm.
这是德林和玛丽安・麦克勒斯特 以及他们的子女
This is Devlin and Maryanne McAllister and their son and daughter.
这个四口之家在家中被枪杀
This is a family of four that was gunned down
因为被怀疑窝藏叛乱份子...
in their own home on suspicion of harboring...
这不关我的事
I am not responsible. ... insurgents.
不知道你是否还能记住其中哪怕一张脸孔
Just wondering if you recognize even one of these faces.
你是否还记得
Did any image get through to you
当你为数不多的冒险走出…
on the rare occasion when you ventured out...
(我不该为被占领…)     那些沙袋掩体...
I am not responsible... ... from behind your sand bags...
(负责…)      和铁丝网的时候…
...for the occupation... ... and your razor wire...
也不该为屠杀负责…
...any more than I am for the genocide.
看到你的人民所遭受的一切！ 他们是你的子民！
...to see what was happening to your people? Your people!
我现在就想知道!  泰上校!  进来!
I need to know! Now! Colonel Tigh, get in here!
把这个人给我带出去    (你不是想)
Get this man out of here. This is not about uncovering...
他不会交代了    (审讯出些什么)
He's not gonna talk. ... any legitimate threat.
把他带走 把他从最近的…
I want you to take him. I want you to toss him...
(你这是…)    ...过渡舱扔出去
This is about getting... ... out the nearest airlock.
...要公报私仇 该死的
...your pound of flesh! About frakking time.
守卫! 快进来
You guards, get in here, now!
那对我的公平审判呢?  把他给我拖出去
What happened to my fair trial? Get rid of him! Take him out of here!
把手拿开 别他妈的碰我!
Take your hands off me! Get your mother-frakking hands off me!
我要求得到公正审判!  我是殖民地公民
I demand a fair trial! I am a citizen of the Colonies,
我要求得到公正审判  公正审判!
and I demand a fair trial! A fair trial!
你给我好好看看  博士
ROSLIN: Take a good look, Doctor.
这些人只是被你送上刑场的人中的一小部分
These are just a fraction of the people you sent to their death.
正好让他们目送你  为你送行
Rather fitting they should see you take your last steps.
停下  等等  停下!        什么事?  什么事?
Stop! Stop! Wait! Stop! What? What!
你问我是否认识 这些人当中的任何一个        对!
You asked if I know any of these people. Yes!
我认识那个人    指出来! 指给我看!  放开他!
I know that man. Show me! Show me! Let him go!
放开他!  把枪举起来!
Let him go! Keep your guns on him!
这个人 他叫艾德里安・鲍尔
This man! His name was Adrien Bauer.
在卡布里卡当过我三年的实验室助理
He was my lab assistant for three years on Caprica.
那又怎样?!  他是杰米纳人
So, what? He was Gemonese.
我帮他拿到了签证 给他介绍了女朋友
I got him a visa. I introduced him to his wife.
我是他第一个孩子的干爹
I am godfather to their first child.
我不会做出任何伤害他或他的家人
I wouldn't do anything to harm this man or his family.
或其他人的家庭的事  我不是杀人犯!
Or anybody's family! I am not a murderer!
我是无辜的!  为什么你们不相信我!?
I am innocent! Why won't you believe me?
抓住他! 把他给我带出去!
Get it! Take him out here!
这就是你们所谓的殖民公正吗?!        把他带出去!
Is this what you call Colonial justice? GUARD: Get him up.
我为你所做的事呢?
What did I ever do for you, huh?
我他妈的救了你的命!
Only saved your bleeding life!
你尽力了    我明白
You gave it your best shot. I understand.
那杂种还是不肯说
Yeah, but the bastard still wouldn't talk.
不是这家伙比我想象的更有种
Either he's got more stones than I gave him credit for, or...
就是他知道你们在虚张声势
Or he knew you were bluffing.
现在该怎么处置他?
Well, what do we do with him now?
还有一个办法
There is one thing.
上将?
Admiral?
军方曾实验性地开展了一项采用药品介入的审讯项目
Military once ran an experimental interrogation program involving drugs.
确切地说  是迷幻剂
Hallucinogens, specifically.
该项目旨在营造一种异常焦虑的状态
The goal of the program was to create a state of anxiety so intense
迫使实验对象认为自己有生命危险
that the subject believed that their very survival was at stake.
审讯员可以利用这点
Interrogators would exploit that,
使其认为对方已经"化敌为友"
become less an adversary and more a lifeline.
至少是要达到这样一个目的 这么做可能会让波塔尔开口交代
At least, that was the idea. It might get Baltar to talk,
说出赛昂人对地球都知道些什么
tell us what the Cylons know about Earth.
但存在危险性 尤其对像波塔尔这种状态的人来说
But it's dangerous, especially for someone in Baltar's condition.
你是说卡拉狄加上有这种药?
Are you telling me we have these drugs aboard Galactica?
你可真是乐于助人
You're being awfully accommodating.
我们的关系  对你来说就是这样?
Is that how it looks to you?
你两地分居红杏出墙的贱老婆 把你叫来"速战速决"
Your estranged, two-timing bitch of a wife calls you up for a quickie,
然后你完事后就要走人?
and you hop on the first shuttle?
我看是这样
I'd say yeah.
我一直在考虑一些事 卡拉
I've been thinking about some stuff, Kara.
是吗?  什么事?
Oh, yeah? Like what?
像是...
Like...
那个疯子"整容人"李・奥本 所说的有关你
What that crazy skin job Leoben said about you
和你的特殊宿命的事  如果确有其事呢?
and your special destiny. What if there's something to that?
"卡拉・瑟瑞丝与她的特殊宿命"?
Kara Thrace and her special destiny?
听起来更像是一支不入流的乐队
That sounds more like a bad cover band, Sam.
还是想一下吧
Think about it, though.
如果我要弃你而去 为什么还能在卡布里卡上
Why did I survive all of those months on Caprica, waiting for you to return,
坚持几个月等你回来?
if I was just gonna walk out on you?
而你...
And you...
历经磨难 被关在那栋破房子里
I mean, did you go through that hell, locked in that fake house
和你那冒牌老公在一起 这样就能甩掉我了吗?
with that fake husband, just so you could ditch me?
我看不能
I don't think so.
我一想到这里的时候...
You know, when I think about it like that...
你爱他吗?
Do you love him?
什么?
What?
李  卡拉  你爱他吗?
Lee. Kara, do you love Lee?
老天  山姆--
Gods, Sam, I...
可能吧 不知道
Maybe. I don't know.
那你就要去找他
Then you gotta go to him.
你不是不值班么
I thought you were off duty.
对
I am. Yeah.
我正要到酒吧坐会
I was just gonna stop by the bar for a little while.
你要是去见卡拉  倒不如直说
If you're gonna see Kara, just admit it.
我已经说过我们之间没什么
Look, I told you. There's nothing going on.
你们都和我说...
Yeah, you both told me,
"李不会对你不忠的 他品德高尚"
"Lee won't cheat. He's too noble. "
可问题是 这都是瞎说的吧?
Only problem is, it's all a crock, isn't it?
你知道问题是什么吗?
You know what the only problem is?
问题是你不信任我  就这么简单
The only problem is that you don't trust me. That's it.
这都是你疑神疑鬼后的胡言乱语 一向如此
And this is just your own frakking insecurities talking, same as always.
从一开始就这样
I mean, right from the get-go,
从我向你求婚的那天早上
the very first morning that I proposed, I mean...
还是算了吧  说多了他妈的也没用
You know what? Forget it. This is frakking pointless.
对  你说对了
No. You're right.
这一切我早料到了
I did see this coming.
可我还是抱有幻想嫁给了你
And I was naive enough to marry you, anyway.
想知道为什么吗?  李
And you want to know why, Lee?
因为那时我爱你
Because I loved you.
太爱你了
I loved you so frakking much.
我以为自己是幸运的
I thought I was lucky.
对 撞了大运
That's right. Lucky.
以为只要你愿意  卡拉愿意 我就能和你长相厮守
That I could have you for just as long as you, or Kara, would let me.
小杜  来  过来
Dee... Come on, give me...
这不是婚姻  李
It's not a marriage, Lee.
这是谎言
This is a lie.
你想和卡拉在一起?  去吧
You want to be with Kara? Go ahead.
我不会碍你的事
I won't stand in your way.
我们之间结束了
It's over.
等等  你要去哪里?
Wait, wait. Where are you going?
山姆
Sam...
我得走了
I gotta get going.
很好
This was fun.
我爱你
I love you.
我是人  我是人  我有权利
BALTAR: I'm a human being. I'm a human being, I have rights.
我说过我有权利
I said I have rights.
求求你  救我
Please, help me.
我看我帮不了你  盖尤斯
I'm not sure I can, Gaius.
痛苦是一方面 但这样…
Pain is one thing, but this?
没有了自力更生的能力 你算是什么了?
Without free will, what are you?
神能够怜悯这样的生物吗?
Can God even pity such a creature?
为什么不承认你之所以这么做 是为了你的一己私欲?
Why not just admit you're doing this for your own satisfaction?
这才是事实  对吧?
That's the truth, isn't it?
为什么你不亲自来把针插进去?
I don't know why you're not putting the needle in yourself.
按住他的头    不 不 不 不
COTTLE: Hold his head. Oh, no! No! No! No! No! Oh, God!
他失去意识了
He's under.
尽量不要喧哗
Try not to make any loud noise.
把头带戴上
Put the head strap on.
我在哪里?
Where am I?
我的天  我这是在哪里?
My God, where am I?
什么意思?
What are you saying?
如果我离开山姆 你还会离开小杜吗?
If I leave Sam, will you still leave Dee?
天啊  卡拉
My Gods, Kara.
我怎么知道你明天不会来个180度的转变?
How do I know that tomorrow you're not going to pull another 180?
我们谈论的可他妈的是婚姻大事
I mean, these are our frakking marriages we're talking about.
不是儿戏啊
It's not some stupid dogfight we can just jink our way out of.
考虑一下吧  李 这是你的强项
Think about it, Lee. That's what you're best at.
我在哪里?
Where am I?
我的天  我在哪里?
My God, where am I?
能听见我说话吗?  能听见吗  博士?
ADAMA: Can you hear my voice? Can you hear me, Doctor?
上将  是你吗?        我在找你  博士
Admiral, is that you? I'm looking for you, Doctor.
找不到你 能告诉我们你在哪里吗?
I can't find you. Can you tell us where you are?
水
It's water.
我在水里 又黑又冷
I'm in the water. It's cold and it's dark.
我什么都看不见
I can't see anything!
你能看到任何可以让我们找到你的东西吗?
Is there anything you can see that can tell us where you are?
找灯  能看到灯吗?      能
Look for the light. Can you see the light? Yes!
伸手去够灯
Try to reach for the light.
就这样
That's it.
跟着灯光走
Yes. Follow the light.
卡布里卡
Caprica.
卡布里卡六号
Caprica Six.
是她救了我 她用身体挡住了气浪
She saved my life. She shielded me from the explosion.
博士 是你与她共谋 破坏了我们的防御系统吗?
Doctor, did you conspire with her to subvert our defense system?
阴谋需要有目的
Conspiracy requires intent!
我从没想要…
I never intended.
可她说再进一步看看  我一直都有所怀疑
But she said deep down, I'd always suspected.
但我不知道
But I didn't know.
我怎么会知道?
How could I know?
我与她共谋了吗?  共谋了吗?
Did I conspire? Did I?
没有
No!
我不知道 不知道
I don't know. No!
不是我的错 不是我的错!
It wasn't my fault. It wasn't my fault!
不是我的责任!
I am not responsible!
是她…
She...
卡布里卡六号 她选择了我
Caprica Six, she chose me.
所有男人之中  她选择了引诱我我
Chose me over all men, chosen to be seduced.
牵着我的手
Taken by the hand,
我被领到光明与黑暗之间
guided between the light and the dark.
可她是天使  还是恶魔?
But is she an angel or is she a demon?
是虚幻的  还是真实的?
Is she imaginary or is she real?
她是我内心的声音吗?
Is she my own voice or the voice of...
我漂不住了
I can't stay afloat much longer!
那就告诉我们详情  博士  赛昂人的详细情况
Now give us details, Doctor. Give us details about the Cylons,
不然我们会让你淹死
or we'll let you drown.
独自在黑暗中死去
Alone, in the dark.
轮机长
Hey, Chief.
怎么他妈的就那么难?
Why is it so frakking hard?
我们为什么就不能恢复正常?
Why can't we just get back to normal?
正常?
Normal?
怎样才算是正常?
What is normal, anyway?
轮机长  如果我说得过分 你就告诉我
Now, Chief, you can tell me if I'm out of line here,
可是...
but...
你会想莎伦吗?
Do you ever think about Sharon?
不会
No.
少来了
Come on.
就没想过"如果"?
You never wonder, "What if?"
没有
No.
别丢下我!  我知道我有缺点
No! Don't leave me! Don't leave me! I know I'm flawed!
我从没说过没有    对 错误 错误发生了
I never claimed to be... Yes, mistakes. Mistakes were made.
大错特错
Terrible mistakes!
是我的过错吗?  只怪我一个人吗?
Were they mine? Am I solely to blame?
我只是一个玩家而已 一个玩家 我拼命想找到
I was a player. That's all I was, a player! I was struggling to...
自己在神的计划中的地位
Struggling to find my place in God's plan,
神的决定中的位置
God's resolve. I...
我从没想过会发生这种事 难道这还不行吗?
I never intended for certain things to happen! Doesn't that matter?
你把赛昂人带到了神庙
You took the Cylons to the Temple.
带到了"朱庇特之眼"那里  他们从那里得到了什么情报?
To the Eye of Jupiter. What did it tell them?
得到了什么有关地球的消息?
What did it tell them about Earth?
我不是在找…
I wasn't looking for...
那你在找寻什么  博士?
What were you looking for, Doctor?
在找寻什么?
What were you looking for?
他们的模样 可他们不愿意让我看到
Their faces, but they wouldn't show them to me.
他们的模样?  谁的模样?
Their faces? Whose faces?
那五个人
The Five.
"终极五人"
The Final Five.
"终极五人"?   赛昂人?
The Final Five? Cylons?
我本以为自己是他们中的一员
I thought I might be one of them.
我对他们说过 我想成为他们中的一员
I told them I wanted to be one of them.
成为赛昂人?  为什么?
A Cylon. Why?
我所有的罪过都会被宽恕
All my sins forgiven.
一个新的开始
A new beginning.
你是赛昂人吗  波塔尔博士?
Are you a Cylon, Doctor Baltar?
不是
No.
空口无凭  博士  说
That's not good enough, Doctor. Tell me.
你都和赛昂人说了什么?
Tell me what you told the Cylons.
他们都知道了什么?  告诉我 不然我就让你淹死
What do they know? Tell me, or I'll have to let you go, Doctor.
我就让你淹死 告诉我 不然我就让你淹死
I'll have to let you go. Tell me, or I'll have to let you go, Doctor.
我就让你淹死
I'll have to let you go.
瞧着点儿!
Watch where you're going.
我的戒指丢了
I lost my ring.
有人看到我的戒指了吗?  我的戒指丢了
Has anybody seen my ring? I lost my ring.
有人看到我的戒指了吗?
Has anybody seen my ring?
我的戒指丢了
I lost my ring!
上将!  他快不行了      够了
Admiral! We're losing him! That's enough.
这场荒唐的实验就到此为止吧
I'm putting an end to this freak show right now.
听这段
ROSLIN: Now, listen to this.
"五个终极型号的赛昂人
"Five final Cylon models.
神庙内的五根柱子对应的五位牧师
"Five Pillars of the Temple for the Five Priests
把生命献给了一个人 这个人的名字不可以被说出来"
"devoted to the One Whose Name Cannot Be Spoken. "
算了吧 这些都是天书
Come on, it's all just mumbo-jumbo.
他还留有好多情报没说 这我可以肯定
He's holding a lot back, Admiral. I'm sure of it.
可能我们要采取一些更直接的方法
Then maybe we should resort to more direct methods.
"直接的方法"?        我支持
Direct methods. Now you have my vote.
不
No.
我们威逼过了
We've tried the stick.
该试试利诱了
It's time to try the carrot.
我看他最担心的就是就算他交代了 我们还是会杀了他
The thing he's most deeply afraid of is that even if he talks, we'll kill him.
聪明人
Smart man.
我们必须减轻他的顾虑
We have to ease his fear.
让他相信如果他合作
Make him believe that, if he collaborates,
至少还能保全性命
at the very least he'll have his life.
我们这么说  他不会相信
He won't buy that coming from us.
那是当然
Of course not.
我们必须要找一个他信任的人
We have to find someone he trusts.
说出来  可能你觉得我很变态
As perverse as it may seem,
但我可能真欠这些人一个人情
I may actually owe these people a debt of gratitude.
我知道也许一切都无法回头
Now, I realize there's probably nothing I can say that can make this right.
但有些事你有要知道
But there's something you need to know.
我会向你求婚 是因为我爱你
I asked you to marry me because I was in love with you.
就像现在我爱你一样
Just like I'm in love with you now.
他们强迫我...
They forced me.
承认我的失败
To admit my failings.
而现在我…  我真是觉得如释重负
And now that I have, I feel positively liberated.
你说得对
You were right.
我爱过卡拉
I loved Kara.
也许 我心里还会有她的位置
You know? And maybe there's a part of me that always will.
说心里话
In my heart,
我一直在做...
I know I have always done
我该做的事
what I've had to do.
但我是和你结婚
But I married you.
我和你结婚了
I married you.
回首我们的婚姻
And, you know, when I look back at our marriage,
我们一起走过的日子
at the time that we have spent together,
我们真的很般配  小杜
you are good for me, Dee.
我需要你
And I need you.
直到我快要失去你时
And I don't think I ever really realized that
我才意识到这点
until I knew that I was losing you.
你能否得到公正审判 我无法保证  博士
I can't promise you a trial, Doctor.
但我确信如果你可以提供任何情报的话
I am sure that if you give them something, anything...
可求你 我只要求你再给我一次机会
But please just give me another chance. That's all I'm asking.
再给我一次机会
Just give me the chance.
我一直在用这些图表来设计我们前往地球的路线
These charts that I've been using to plot our course to Earth?
我一直对自己的运算没信心
I've never been confident about my calculations.
似乎这些运算是错误的
Well, that's likely because the calculations are wrong.
我发现一些数字不一致
I detect a number of inconsistencies right off the bat.
这些数字是错误的
You see, these figures here are wrong.
这正是我所担心的
That's exactly what I was afraid of.
赛昂人的导航系统远比我们的先进得多
Cylon navigation systems are far more advanced than our own,
但我已经记住他们的算法
but I have managed to commit many of the algorithms to memory.
如果我们能在这点上帮助他们
If we can offer them this kind of help,
我敢肯定他们至少会饶你一命
I'm certain, at the very least, they will spare your life.
或许我们能让你离开这牢房
Maybe we can even get you out of this cell,
给你找个合适的房间
offer you some proper quarters.
说到底 这就是生物好逸恶劳的本性
Creature comforts, that's the clincher.
什么?
Sorry?
在哪里?
Where is it?
什么在哪里 博士?  "什么在哪里? "
Where is what, Doctor? "Where is what?"
没戏唱了
So much for that little stratagem.
你好
Hello.
嗨
Hey...
你还好吧?
You all right?
要是你不想在这里 我们这就走  好吗?
Listen, we don't have to stay here if you don't want to, okay?
好
Yeah.
两杯威士忌  倒满
Two whiskeys, straight up.
我早该料到是你会背叛我
I should have known that you would betray me.
你都告诉他们什么了?
What did you tell them?
在新卡布里卡的末日到来之前 你一直是幕后英雄?
That you stayed behind until the grisly end on New Caprica so you could, what?
如此一来才可以怎么样?
So you could...
给抵抗军提供情报?
You could feed information to the Resistance?
你以为是谁 让你如此顺心如意的?
Who do you think allowed you to do that?
你说谎    不 我没说谎 你以为我瞎了吗?
That's a lie. No, it's not a lie. You think I'm blind?
我之所以那么做其实是有人用枪指着我的头
You see, I literally had a gun pointed to my head.
可没人逼你当两面派
But nobody forced you to play both sides.
我问你  盖塔先生
So I'm asking you, Mr. Gaeta,
这房间里谁才是叛徒?
who is the real traitor in this room?
为未来干杯
To the first of many.
再来一杯?    好
Let's do another. Yeah.
我不是叛徒    当然不是
I am not a traitor. No, of course.
那是因为有些事
Because there are... There are far worse things
比叛变更严重 对吧  菲里克斯?
than being a traitor, aren't there, Felix?
只要让你的朋友知道了真相
If your friends only knew the truth.
别担心 那是我们之间的小秘密
Don't worry. It's our little secret.
我们得马上过去
We've gotta get in there.
离开我
Get away from me!
去你妈的!
Frak you!
盖塔中尉 立即离开犯人
GUARD: Lieutenant Gaeta. Step away from the prisoner, now.
离开犯人 这是最后警告
Step away from the prisoner! I will not ask you again!
放下枪  中士        是  长官
Stand down, Sergeant. Yes, sir.
退后  盖塔先生        不行  长官
Step back, Mr. Gaeta. No. No! No, sir!
他恶贯满盈 我不能放过他
I can't... I can't let him live. Not after what he's done.
盖塔先生 盖塔先生  请等等 看着我
Mr. Gaeta? Mr. Gaeta, wait. Please. Look at me.
我理解你的感受
I understand what you're feeling.
不  你不理解        不  我理解
GAETA: No, you don't. Yes, I do.
那天晚上 你不是来审问波塔尔博士
The other night, you didn't come here to interrogate Doctor Baltar.
而是来杀他的  对吧?        我理解  真的
You came here to kill him, didn't you? I understand that. I do.
他的伤势如何?        没伤到动脉  死不了
What's his condition? He missed the artery. He'll live.
最好把他送到医务室 快取个担架过来
We've got to get him to sick bay. Get a gurney in here right away.
慢点
ROSLIN: Go easy on him.
都考虑周全了 盖尤斯  否则结果可能更糟糕
NO. 6: All things considered, Gaius, it could have been worse.
糟糕的很
Much worse.
虽然你不是五人之一
Well, you're not one of the Five.
但你还是得到了神的庇佑
You certainly have the luck of the Gods.
不  我是被神选中的人
Well, I am the Chosen One.
你没和他们说这些  对吧?
You didn't tell them that, did you?
没有
No.
每个人都有秘密
Everybody's got to have a secret.
我告诉他看到他受罪 我并不感到满足
I told him I didn't take any satisfaction in seeing his pain.
可其实为了达到目的 我很愿意
But the truth is, I was willing to see him endure a great deal of suffering
看到他痛苦煎熬的样子
in order to get what I wanted.
并不是想要得到什么情报 或是什么真相
It wasn't some intelligence or some truth.
我只想看到他 为自己所犯的罪行而真正地内疚
I wanted a genuine admission of guilt.
从波塔尔这种人身上 你不会得到这些
That's something that you're not gonna get from someone like Baltar.
他自己可不那么认为
He doesn't see himself that way.
他不是那种人
That's not who he is.
在他看来  他才是受害者
In his eyes, he's the victim,
而非罪犯
not the criminal.
现在让他就此消失还为时不晚
It's not too late for him to just disappear.
我们不能那么做
We can't do that.
他始终是我们中的一员
For all his crimes, he's one of us.
那下一步怎么办?
So, what happens next?
让他得到公正的审判
We give him his trial.